The Music Records of United Church
Yale University Music Library
The Music Records of United Church
1794-1910
Misc. Ms. 339
Yale University Music Library
0.25
(1 box)
Correspondence, receipts, and other documents concerning musical activities at the United Church on the Green of New Haven, Connecticut between 1794 and 1910
United Church on the Green (New Haven, Conn.)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
In 3 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Receipts. III. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents musical matters in New Haven's United Church Society from 1794 to 1910. Included are correspondence, receipts, and miscellaneous items concerning the purchase and upkeep of organs, the hiring and payment of singers, and other matters concerning the musical life of the church.
Biographical / Historical
The United Church of New Haven, Connecticut traces its origins back to 1742, when the "New Lights" (supporters of the Great Awakening) separated from the existing Congregational church in New Haven. The current building was constructed in 1816. Formerly called North Church, it is now known as the United Church on the Green; it is the northernmost of the three churches built in a row on the New Haven Green.
Church music -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Organ (Musical instrument) -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Singers -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Read, Daniel, 1757-1836; United Church on the Green (New Haven, Conn.)
- Correspondence, Series I
  - 1818-1881, 11 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1905-1910, 4 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - n.d., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Receipts, Series II
  - 1794-1820, 10 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1821-1835, 28 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1836-1861, 35 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1864-1868, 34 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1869-1872, 32 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  - Ledger book recording hymns and readings, 1898-1904; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Separate manuscript record (1 p.) laid in.
  - The United Church, Brochure, Dec. 30, 1894; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fragments with manuscript notes, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 4)